[音樂]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：我會給你出一系列問題。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I'm gonna give you a series of problems.
問題可能如下所示。
A problem might look like this.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：編寫一個接受引數和
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Write an identity function that takes an argument and
返回該引數。
returns that argument.
我會舉一個例子來說明你會怎麼稱呼它
And I'll show an example of how you would call it and
那通電話的結果會是什麼。
what the result of that call would be.
然後我會給你一些時間來做這件事。
I will then give you some time to work on it.
大概十分鐘左右吧。
Probably about ten minutes or so.
你們中的一些人會比其他人工作得更快，所以
Some of you are gonna work faster than others, so for
你們中那些完成得很快的人，你們會很沮喪的，
those of you who finish quickly, you're gonna get frustrated,
因為你得等時間我們才能繼續。
because you're gonna have to wait for the time before we go on.
對於你們中的一些人來說，工作速度會變慢，你們會感到沮喪
And for some of you are gonna be working slower, and you're gonna get frustrated
因為你可能沒有足夠的時間來完成每一道題。
cuz you might not have enough time to finish every problem.
所以，我今天的目標是平等地挫敗每個人，好嗎？
So, my goal today is to frustrate everybody equally, okay?
這就是我們要帶著這個去的地方。
That's where we're gonna be going with this.
所以，你需要一些時間，
So, you'll take some time,
你會解決這個問題，你會想出解決辦法的。
you'll work on the problem, you'll come up with the solution.
然後我會給你看我的解決方案。
I will then show you my solution.
在某些情況下，我可能會向您展示多種解決方案
And in some cases, I may show you multiple solutions and
你可以把你的和我的比較一下。
you can compare yours with mine.
如果你喜歡我的勝過你的，你想錄下來，
If you like mine better than yours, you want to record it,
因為後面的每一個問題都會涉及到前面的問題。
because each of these later problems will refer to earlier problems.
或者在模式中，或者我們將實際呼叫前面的函式，
Either in pattern or we'll actually be calling the earlier functions,
因此，請確保您至少獲得了所有可以正常工作的版本。
so make sure that you get at least one version of everything that works.
另外，我強烈建議您使用與我完全相同的函式名，
Also, I highly recommend that you use exactly the same function names that I do,
因為稍後我們將編寫呼叫這些函式的函式，如果您
because later we're gonna write functions which call these functions, and if you're
給他們不同的名字，真的很容易混淆，好嗎？
giving them different names, it'll be really easy to get confused, okay?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：那麼你可能會想要測試一下。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Then you'll probably want to test it.
例如，如果您的計算機上有JavaScript引擎以及如何使用它，
If you have a JavaScript engine on your machine and how to use it, for example,
如果您安裝了Node，並且知道如何使用repo，那就太好了。
if you have Node installed and you know how to use the repo, that's great.
你只要把它插在那裡，它就能用了。
You can just plug it in there, and it'll work.
如果沒有，您至少有一個Web瀏覽器。
If you don't, you have at least one web browser.
現在所有的網路瀏覽器都有非常好的偵錯程式，所以
And all the web browsers now come with very nice debuggers, so
你也可以這麼做。
you can do that as well.
這是使用Web瀏覽器的一種方式。
This is one way to use a web browser.
您可以簡單地擁有一個類似這樣的表單，或者一個包含指令碼標記的頁面。
You could simply have a form like this, or a page containing a script tag.
為了方便起見，我建立了一個日誌函式，這樣我就可以記錄結果，
For my convenience, I created a log function so I could log results,
它會直接把它們寫到螢幕上。
and it'll just write them to the screen.
然後在盒子裡，我有我寫的函式，
Then in the box, I've got the function that I wrote, and
然後我呼叫函式，將結果傳送到日誌。
then I called the function sending the result to the log.
如果你想做更復雜的事，
If you wanna do something more sophisticated,
當然歡迎你去做那件事。
you're certainly welcome to do that.
這在某種程度上是您入門所需的最低要求。
This is sort of the minimum that you need to get started.
您不需要測試您的功能，但是您可能想測試一下，對嗎？
You don't have to test your functions, but you probably want to, right?
因為否則的話，你就不能相信它們工作正常。
Cuz otherwise you can't have confidence that they're working correctly.
當每個人都還在準備的時候，我們要做個測驗。
While everybody is still getting set up, we're gonna do a quiz.
突擊測驗。
Pop quiz.
我們開始吧，準備好了嗎？
So here we go, ready?
第一個問題，我們有一個叫做Funky的函式。
Question number one, we have a function called funky.
它接受引數o，將o設定為空。
It takes an argument o, sets o to null.
我們建立一個全域性變數x，它是一個空陣列，我們將x傳遞給Funky。
We create a global variable x, which is an empty array, we pass x to funky.
現在x的值是多少？
What is now the value of x?
那麼誰認為x為空呢？
So who thinks x is null?
誰認為x是空陣列呢？
And who thinks x is the empty array?
誰認為它是不確定的呢？
And who thinks it's undefined?
誰認為它會丟擲一個例外呢？
And who thinks it'll throw an exception?
好的，答案是B，空陣列。
Okay, the answer is B, the empty array.
那麼讓我們來看看這裡發生了什麼。
So let's look at what's happening here.
所以如果我們開始，我們有指向陣列的全域性變數x。
So if we start off, we have the global variable x that points at the array.
我們傳遞x的內容，這是對Funky的引用，
We pass the contents of x, which is that reference to funky,
這使它與o繫結在一起。
which has it bound to o.
我們用NULL替換o。
We replace o with null.
然後你就來了。
And then there you are.
所以，就像寫的那樣，時髦是一個完全無用的功能。
So funky, as written, is a completely useless function.
在這方面，變數的工作方式並不是JavaScript獨有的。
And in this thing about the way variables work is not peculiar to JavaScript.
幾乎所有的現代語言都是這樣工作的。
Almost all modern languages work this way.
大多數語言都不允許您傳遞對變數的引用。
Most languages do not allow you to pass a reference to a variable.
它們允許您做的是傳遞對內容的引用
What they allow you to do is to pass a reference to the contents of
變數，好的。
the variable, okay.
ALGOL 60是一種很棒的語言，裡面有一種叫做，
ALGOL 60, which was a brilliant language, had something in it called,
按名稱呼叫，實際上可以傳遞對變數的引用。
call by name, where you actually could pass a reference to a variable.
這是ALGOL 60中為數不多的、非常糟糕的想法之一。
That was one of the very few, very bad ideas in ALGOL 60.
準備好再來一次了嗎？
Ready for another one?
好的，這是一個函式交換，有兩個引數a和b，
Okay, here's a function swap, takes two arguments a and b, and
它使用TEMP變數交換它們。
it swaps them using a temp variable.
我們有兩個全域性變數x和y，它們的值是1和2。
We have two global variables, x and y, whose values are 1 and 2.
我們把x和y傳遞給交換，現在x的值是多少？
We pass x and y to swap, what is now the value of x?
道格拉斯·克羅克福德：那麼誰認為x是1呢？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So who thinks x is 1?
誰認為x是2？
Who thinks x is 2?
好吧，這次我不會騙你的。
Okay I'm not gonna fool you this time.
答案是1。
The answer is 1.
這和我們之前做的類似。
And it's similar to what we did before.
這裡我們有兩個全域性變數，x和y，指向1和2。
So here we've got our two global variables, x and y, that point to 1 and 2.
我們將x和y傳遞給交換。
We pass x and y to swap.
然後我們用掉期交易來擺弄他們，但是
Then we fiddle them around with swap, but
這並沒有改變x和y正在做的事情。
that did not change what x and y are doing.
我希望在未來的某一天，JavaScript可以獲得巨集。
I'm hoping that some day in the future, JavaScript gets macros.
所以我不會說函式互換，我會說巨集觀互換。
So instead of saying function swap, I'd say macro swap.
在這種情況下，巨集確實會被呼叫，或者確實會用變數名傳遞，並且
And in that case, macros do get called or do get passed with variable names, and
巨集互換是有用的，但是正如所寫的那樣，函式互換是非常無用的。
macro swap would be useful thing, but as written, function swap is pretty useless.
好的，關於測驗有什麼問題嗎？
Okay, any questions about the quiz?
好了，測驗結束了。
Okay, quiz is done.
是時候做點實實在在的工作了，你準備好了嗎？
It's time to do some real work, are you ready?
所以第一個是非常瑣碎的，沒有花招，
So the first one is going to be totally trivial, no tricks,
它只是允許您測試您的環境的東西。
it's just something to allow you to test your environment.
所以寫三個二進位制函式。
So write three binary functions.
二進位制函式是接受兩個引數的函式。
A binary function is a function that takes two arguments.
ADD、SUB和MUL，它們接受兩個數字，並返回它們的和、差和
Add, sub and mul, that take two numbers and return their sum, difference and
產品，好的。
product, okay.
這聽起來很微不足道。
This is as trivial as it sounds.
沒有什麼詭計。
There are no tricks.
我們這麼做是為了讓你可以練習
We're doing this so that you can practice and also so
我們將擁有稍後編寫的函式可以呼叫的函式。
that we'll have functions that functions that we write later will be able to call.
所以這裡我們有加法、第一法和多法。
So here we have add, first and mul.
我想每個人都有這個，對吧？
I assume that everybody got this, right?
是的，這是誰拍的？
Yes, who got this?
是的，如果你沒有，那就寫下來，因為你以後會用到這些的。
Yeah, if you didn't, write it down because you're going to need these for later.
好了，準備好今天第一個有趣的問題了嗎？
Okay, ready for the first interesting problem of the day?
我們開始吧。
Here we go.
編寫一個接受引數的函式標識f，並
Write a function identityf that takes an argument and
返回返回該引數的函式。
returns a function that returns that argument.
因此，我們將其命名為身份f，我們將傳遞它3。
So, we're gonna call it identityf, we're gonna pass it 3.
這將返回一個函式。
That will return a function.
當我們呼叫該函式時，它將返回3。
When we call that function, it will return 3.
那麼，這就是身份f。
So, here is identityf.
Identityf接受一個引數並返回返回該引數的函式。
identityf takes an argument and returns a function that returns that argument.
那麼誰拿到身份了？
So who got identityf?
非常好。
Very good.
如果你沒拿到，就寫下來，
If you didn't get it, write it down,
因為你以後肯定需要它。
because you gotta definitely need it later.
不要氣餒，我並不是期望每個人都能解決所有的問題。
And don't be discouraged, I'm not expecting everybody to get every problem.
我期望的是每個人都能得到最後一個問題。
What I'm expecting is that everybody gets the last problem.
好的，如果你看不到馬上會發生什麼，就繼續看著它。
Okay, so if you don't see what's going on immediately, just stay with it.
最終，這些模式應該會開始變得更加清晰
Eventually the patterns should start to become clearer and
你會知道我們要去哪裡的，好嗎？
you'll get a sense of where we're going, okay?
到目前為止還有什麼問題嗎？
Any questions so far?
好的，我們準備好下一場了嗎？
Okay, are we ready for the next one?
好的，編寫一個從兩次呼叫相加的函式ADDF。
Okay, write a function addf that adds from two invocations.
因此，如果我們將3傳遞給ADDF，它將返回一個函式。
So if we pass a 3 to addf, it would return a function.
如果我們將4傳遞給該函式，它將返回7。
If we pass 4 to that function, it will return 7.
這就是ADDF。
So here is addf.
ADDF接受第一個引數，它返回接受第二個引數的函式
addf takes a first argument, it returns a function that takes the second argument
並返回呼叫第一個和第二個引數的結果。
and it returns the result of calling the first and second argument.
那麼誰得到了ADDF呢？
So who got addf?
好的，很好。
Okay, very good.
如果你沒有收到，就寫下來。
If you didn't get it, write it down.
下一次你會需要它的。
You're gonna wanna need it for the next one.
這個問題是德米特里·巴拉諾夫斯基向我提出的，
So this problem was suggested to me by Dmitry Baranovskiy,
他是居住在澳大利亞悉尼的一位才華橫溢的烏克蘭程式設計師。
who is a brilliant Ukrainian programmer living in Sydney, Australia.
他是RaphaelJS的作者，這是一個非常好的瀏覽器圖形包。
He's the author of RaphaelJS, a very nice graphics package for the browser.
他建議這應該是一個招聘問題，如果你沒弄錯的話，
He suggested that this should be a hiring question, and if you got this right,
也許你也這麼認為。
maybe you think so, too.
那麼我們準備好下一場了嗎？
So we ready for the next one?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：好的，我們開始吧。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Okay, here we go.
編寫一個函式liftf，該函式接受一個二進位制函式
Write a function liftf that takes a binary function and
使其可通過兩次呼叫來呼叫。
makes it callable with two invocations.
所以，如果我們傳遞今天早上我們編寫的第一件事Add函式
So, if we pass the add function that we wrote the first thing this morning
把它舉起來，
to liftf,
它返回一個工作方式與我們剛才編寫的ADDF函式完全相同的函式。
it returns a function that works exactly like the addf function that we just wrote.
更有趣的是，我們可以傳遞其他的二進位制函式，
And to make it even more interesting, we can pass other binary functions,
喜歡乘法函式，並獲得類似的功能。
like the multiply function, and get a similar kind of capability.
讓我們看一下liftf。
Let's look at liftf.
Liftf接受一個二進位制函式，返回一個接受第一個引數的函式，
Liftf takes a binary function, returns a function that takes a first argument,
它返回一個接受第二個引數的函式，該函式返回
that returns a function that takes a second argument, that returns a result of
將第一和第二引數傳遞給二進位制函式。
passing the first and second arguments to the binary function.
那麼誰被抬走了？
So who got liftf?
非常好。
Very good.
如果你沒有收到，就寫下來。
If you didn't get it, write it down.
以後你會需要它的。
You're gonna want to need it for a later one.
這是一個高階函式的例子。
This is an example of a higher order function.
高階函式是接收其他函式作為引數的函式
Higher order functions are functions that receive other functions as parameters and
將其他函式作為結果返回。
return other functions as results.
所以我們開始往兔子洞裡走，進入一個非常
So we're starting to get moving down the rabbit hole into a very
有趣的建造方式。
interesting way of constructing things.